Cambridge, Mass. Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport records, 1863-1992.
Congregational Library & Archives
Cambridge, Mass. Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport records, 1863-1992.
RG2350
Congregational Library & Archives
7.76 Cubic Feet
(10 boxes)
Stearns Chapel was erected in 1863 and was located on Harvard Street, near Windsor; it was designed primarily as a Mission Sabbath School and operated for a number of years by the First and Second Congregational, Baptist and Methodist churches. The name was changed to Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport in 1871. The collection includes church records, financial records, ministers' records, membership records, auxiliary group records, historical information, orders of service and programs, and photographs and lantern slides.
Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport (Cambridge, Mass.)
Stearns Chapel (Cambridge, Mass.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials gathered by Rev. Norman Bendroth and donated to the Congregational Library & Archives, September 1992, by Warren L. Milley (Chairman, Board of Trustees) for Pilgrim Congregational Church.
Assigned Accession number: 1992-0
Historical Note
Stearns Chapel was erected in 1863 and was located on Harvard Street, near Windsor; it was designed primarily as a Mission Sabbath School (established by Prospect Congregational and neighborhood churches in Cambridgeport in 1852) and operated for a number of years by the First and Second Congregational, Baptist and Methodist churches. In 1865 Mr. Edward Abbott began to hold regular services; by fall the church was formally organized and Abbott installed as minister. The Second Congregational, Baptist and Methodist churches withdrew ca. 1866; in 1871 the First Church also withdrew. The church grew rapidly and a new meetinghouse was completed in 1871 at the corner of Magazine and Cottage Street; the name was changed to Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport in the same year. The church closed in 1992.
Ministers:
William R. Stone: 1863
Edward Abbott: 1865-1869
George R. Leavitt: 1870-1885
George A. Tewksbury: 1885-1889
Charles Olmstead: 1889-1896
Frank E. Ramsdell: 1897-1900
Charles Wesley Gallagher, D.D.: 1900-1902
William H. Spence: 1902-1906
Richard Wright: 1907-1920
Clarence Wells Dunham, D.D.: 1920-1922
Hubert E. Beckwith: 1922-1927
John E. Jaderquist, Ph.D.: 1927-1928
Stanley H. Addison: 1928-1950
Ralph Ernest Bayes, D.D.: 1950-1951
Melvin M. Nyman: 1951-1962
Ralph Ernest Bayes, D.D.: 1962-1963
Philip D. Chamberlain: 1963
Ralph Ernest Bayes, D.D.: 1964
Donald A. Wells: 1964-1969
Glen W. Barker: 1970
David Steele: 1971-1984
D. Stewart, O.D.: 1985
Norman Bendroth: 1986-1992
Scope and Contents
The Pilgrim Congregational Church records document the history and life of the church, beginning with its predecessor church (Stearns Chapel, 1865-1871) and continuing through its closure in 1992. The collection includes church records, financial records, ministers' records, membership records, auxiliary group records (particularly the Women's Guild), historical information, orders of service and programs, and photographs and lantern slides. Records are more comprehensive for the early years of the church (through the early 1930) and the later decades (late 1960s to 1992) than for the middle of the twentieth century (a notable exception is the 75th Anniversary Celebration in 1940, which is well-documented). Researchers should be sure to look at the historical sketches included with the anniversary celebration materials in Series 7.
Arrangement
The Pilgrim Congregational Church records have been arranged into the five series listed below. Series 1 has been further subdivided into five subseries. Within each series materials have been primarily arranged in chronological order by start date. When appropriate, similar and continuous materials have been grouped together.
Series 1: Church administrative records, 1863-1992
Subseries 1: Stearns Chapel records, 1863-1972
Subseries 2: Membership and vital records, 1865-1938
Subseries 3: Committee records, 1871-1991
Subseries 4: Church records, 1871-1992
Subseries 5: Church programming, 1871-1992
Series 2: Financial and building records, 1864-1992
Series 3: Church groups and societies, 1870-1990
Series 4: Ministerial records, 1889-1990
Series 5: Visual materials, 1898-1990
Related Materials
The finished course a sermon commemorative of Thomas Ferrier Jr., who died July 20th 1865 preached at the Stearns Chapel: Cambridgeport, Sabbath, July 30th by Rev. Edward Abbot (1865). Call No.: 15.0.7 6635 FEA-FIT
A Brief History of Pilgrim Church by Rev George R. Leavitt (1889). Call No.: 30.8.1 1004
Cambridge, MA: Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport (1869-1940). Call No.: 17.11.1 C14.24 PILCC
Church correspondence.; Church finance.; Church membership.; Church property.; Church records and registers.; Church societies.; Clergy -- Correspondence.; Installation (clergy).; Necrologies.; Sunday schools.; Wills.; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Worship programs.; Cambridge (Mass.) -- Church history.; Pilgrim Congregational Church of Cambridgeport (Cambridge, Mass.); Stearns Chapel (Cambridge, Mass.)
- Church administrative records, 1863 1992; 1863-1992
  Scope and Contents
  This series, which has been further subdivided into five sub-series, contains the important administrative records of the Pilgrim Congregational Church. This broad designation covers materials related to the daily running of the church, records relating to the church's members, records of administrative committees, and records describing the activities and programs of the church.
  - Stearns Chapel records, 1863 1972; 1863-1972
    This sub-series contains records directly related to the administration of the Stearns Chapel. Records include the Stearns Chapel Manual, membership list, Sabbath School programs, Orders of service, newsletter, correspondence, American Board of Commission for Foreign Missions receipts, and Committee reports for the examination, visiting, and neighborhood prayer meeting committees.
    - Stearns Chapel committee reports, 1863 1971; 1863-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Stearns Chapel records, 1865 1872; 1865-1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership and vital records, 1865 1938; 1865-1938
    This sub-series contains records related to the members of the Pilgrim Congregational Church. This sub-series includes lists of members from various points in time, sporadic vital records, and admissions and dismissions.
    Separated Materials
    One box of membership letters was removed due to mold.
    - Membership book, 1865 1933; 1865-1933 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Pastors, deacons and members lists, 1865 1915; 1865-1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Church register, 1870 1884; 1870-1884 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Vital statistics, 1870 1910; circa 1870-1910 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Examination of candidates, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Admissions, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dismissions, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1897 1900; 1897-1900 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Membership lists, 1889 1897; 1889-1897 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1911 1930; 1911-1930 (Box 5, Folder 12-18)
    - Certificate and covenant, 1920 1929; circa 1920-1929 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Membership lists, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Records of deaths, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Membership lists, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Membership lists, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Committee records, 1871 1991; 1871-1991
    This sub-series contains the records of lay church committies directly related to the administration and day-to-day running of the Pilgrim Congregational Church. Included in the records are meeting minutes, correspondence, reports, and committee lists.
    - Church committee minutes, 1871 1881; 1871-1881 (Box 2, Folder 3-7)
    - Standing committee records, 1881 1884; 1881-1884 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Standing committee financial records, 1887 1890; 1887-1890 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Committee reports, 1878 1881; 1878-1881 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Committee lists, 1886 1926; 1886-1926 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Church committee minutes, 1902 1914; 1902-1914 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
    - Church committee minutes, 1915 1950; 1915-1950 (Box 2, Folder 12-17)
    - Church committee records, 1966 1969; 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Church committee minutes and correspondence, 1971 1984; 1971-1984 (Box 2, Folder 19-23)
    - Church committee minutes and correspondence, 1986 1991; 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    - Church committee nominating committee, 1971 1972; 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Committee lists, 1968 1979; 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Calling committee, 1930 1939; circa 1930-1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Calling committee, 1973 1983; 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Board of deacons' records, 1964 1984; 1964-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29-32)
    - Board of deacons' treasurer's reports, 1987 1988; 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Property committee, 1965 1985; 1965-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Finance committee, 1971 1990; 1971-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Evaluation committee, 1974 1976; 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Planning committee, 1974 1989; 1974-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Elders' and deacons' records, 1980 1990; 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Fellowship committee, 1980 1990; circa 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Music committee, 1984 1991; 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Church records, 1872 1991; 1871-1992
    This sub-series contains records directly produced by the Pilgrim Congregational Church related to the running of the church. The records includes the Act of incorporation, church manuals, annual meeting minutes, annual reports, Deacons' and Trustees' records, Church Committee and Standing Committee records, other committee records, and correspondence. Records books for 1872-1914 and "notes on business meetings" for 1915-1930 have these different types of records together in chronological order, along with some membership records. Committee records (not including the Church Committee) are included for the 1970s-1991 only, and do not provide complete coverage. Correspondence is intermittent.
    Two Books of Church Committee records, covering 1894-1902, were removed from the collection due to mold.
    - Act of incorporation, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Church records, 1872 1914; 1872-1914 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Manual of the Pilgrim Congregational Church, 1873 1930; 1873-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1875 1883; 1875-1883 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1886 1891; 1886-1891 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
    - Correspondence, 1895 1898; 1895-1898 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1915 1919; 1915-1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1920 1950; 1920-1950 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1987 1990; 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Meetings warrants, 1880 1883; 1880-1883 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Meetings warrants, 1888 1891; 1888-1891 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Meetings warrants, 1917 1931; 1917-1931 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Suffolk North Conference meetings & report, 1891 1942; 1891-1942 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Annual reports, 1896 1897; 1896-1897 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Existence of Originals
      This folder contains photocopied facsimiles of the original annual reports. The Congregational Library & Archives does not hold the originals and they are presumed to have been lost or destroyed before the collection's acquisition.
    - Annual reports, 1914 1915; 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Annual reports, 1917 1931; 1917-1931 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Annual reports and correspondence, 1937 1938; 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Annual report and correspondence, 1938 1940; 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Annual reports, 1940 1942; 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Annual reports, 1968 1991; 1968-1991 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - Church histories, 1900 1989; circa 1900-1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Church election ballots, 1906 1915; 1906-1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Notes on business meetings, 1915 1930; 1915-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5-14)
    - Annual and business meeting minutes, 1915 1931; 1915-1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Annual Meetings, 1941 1943; 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Job descriptions, 1980 1989; circa 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Vision task force, 1989 1991; 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Board of trustees' minutes and correspondence, 1991 1992; 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Church programming, 1871 1992; 1871-1992
    This seub-series contains records related to the activities and programs of the Pilgrim Congregational Church. The records include historical sketches, newspaper clippings, and programs and materials from anniversary celebrations, including a large amount of material concerning the 75th Anniversary celebration. Of particular note is the "Memories of Pilgrim Congregational Church" scrapbook, compiled by the pastor and congregation at the time of its closing in 1992. The records also include records of church activities and programs, especially from end of the 19th Century through the first half of the 20th Century and during the 1980s, the church's last decade (including both church-sponsored events and community programs with which the church was involved). These records also include issues of Pilgrim/Cambridgeport Together, a newsletter put out by the church in the late 1980s.
    A copy of "A Brief History of Pilgrim Church" by Rev. George Leavitt (1889) was removed due to mold; a copy of this publication is located in the Congregational Library's holdings.
    - Orders of services, 1871 1930; 1871-1930 (Box 6, Folder 34-40)
    - 10th anniversary celebration and historical discourse, 1875 1876; 1875-1876 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Programs, 1880 1949; circa 1880-1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1889 1969; circa 1889-1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Gospel song service, 1889 1890; 1889-1890 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - 25th anniversary celebration, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - 50th anniversary celebration and historical address, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Orders of services, 1934 1939; 1934-1939 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Orders of service, 1940 1979; circa 1940-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Auditorium renovation and rededication, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 75th anniversary, 1939 1940; 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 17-26)
    - Birthday anniversary calendar, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Fellowship and activities, 1960 1979; circa 1960-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 100th anniversary celebration, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Neighborhood publicity and outreach, 1980 1989; circa 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Together" outreach project, 1987 1990; 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Pilgrim/Cambridgeport together, 1987 1990; 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Pilgrim Congregational Church worship book, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Organ preservation and benefit concert, 1988 1989; 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Peace Camp" Soviet Exchange, 1988 1990; 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Festival of Joy, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Children's Haven" children's program, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - 125th anniversary celebration, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Cambridge clergy for affordable housing, 1990 1991; 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Speakers and events, 1990 1991; 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Summer union services with First United Presbyterian Church, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Multicultural celebration and dedication, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Cambridge after school center, 1991 1992; 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Memories of Pilgrim Congregational Church, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
- Financial and building records, 1864 1992; 1864-1992; 1922 1992; 1922-1992
  This series of financial and building records predominantly consist of ledgers and treasurers' reports. Treasurers' reports up through 1942 are annual reports, while Treasurers' reports from 1971-1992 are predominantly monthly reports, with some annual reports included. Also of note are fundraising letters from the pastor and financial committee, wills, trust account, and records related to the rental and sale of church properties.
  - Property deeds and correspondence, 1864 1929; 1864-1929 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Treasurers' reports and fundraising letters, 1892 1910; 1892-1910 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Treasurers' reports, 1914 1931; 1914-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Fundraising letters, 1919 1938; 1919-1938 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Wills, 1920 1970; circa 1920-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Financial ledgers, 1922 1938; 1922-1938 (Box 3, Volume 19)
  - Statistics for yearbook, 1924 1931; 1924-1931 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Property (Upton and Kinnaird St.) records, 1930 1960; circa 1930-1960 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Property and financial records, 1930 1980; circa 1930-1980 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Treasurers' reports, 1940 1942; 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Building rentals, 1950 1970; circa 1950-1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Financial ledgers, 1956 1982; 1956-1982 (Box 3, Volume 20-25)
  - Financial correspondence, 1959 1969; 1959-1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Financial records, 1959 1971; 1959-1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Stewardship, 1966 1972; 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Church insurance policies, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Offering envelope lists, 1968 1972; 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Offering envelope lists, 1968 1972; 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Stewardship, 1968 1972; 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cash and disbursements, 1969 1980; 1969-1980 (Box 3, Volume 28)
  - Memorial gifts, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Treasurers' report books, 1971 1988; 1971-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Treasurers' reports, 1971 1992; 1971-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
  - James A. Dow trust account, 1972 1989; 1972-1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Budgets, 1975 1980; 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising letters, 1978 1992; 1978-1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Treasurers' records, 1980 1989; circa 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Treasurers' records, 1980 1989; circa 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Proposal for new initiatives in church development funding, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Tax returns, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Restrictions on Access
    These materials are confidential and not available to the public.
  - Check registers, 1986 1987; 1986-1987 (Box 3, Volume 29)
  - Financial ledgers, 1987 1988; 1987-1988 (Box 3, Volume 26)
  - Alice J. Coolidge trust account, 1987 1989; 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Financial ledgers, 1990 (Box 3, Volume 27)
- Church groups and societies, 1870 1990; 1870-1990
  This series contains the records of various church societies and auxillary groups. The most complete set of records is for the Women's Guild Service Club and its antecedents, the Women's Guild and the Ladies' Aid Society. The financial records for these groups from 1895-1962 include membership lists; the records books from 1934-1973 include minutes and annual reports. The series also include records for a small number of other social groups, the Sunday School and other Christian education groups, and the Missions Committee Records for the 1965-1990.
  - Little Pilgrim Catechism and Missions Class, 1870 1889; circa 1870-1889 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Sunday School Programs, 1874 1923; 1874-1923 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sunday School Annual and Treasurers' Reports, 1923 1931; 1923-1931 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Sunday School Annual and Treasurers' Reports, 1941 1943; 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1889 1949; circa 1889-1949 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Ladies' Aid Society: Pilgrim Serving Society Cash Book, 1895 1916; 1895-1916 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Ladies' Aid Society Treasurer's Books, 1915 1937; 1915-1937 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Women's Missionary Society Secretary's Record Book, 1905 1912; 1905-1912 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Philia Club, 1930 1950; 1930-1950 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Women's Guild Missionary, Financial, Membership, 1934 1966; 1934-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Women's Guild Annual Reports, 1934 1966; 1934-1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Women's Guild Records, 1934 1966; 1934-1966 (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
  - Women's Guild Minutes, 1966 1973; 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Women's Guild Service Club, 1975 1978; 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Service Club, 1940 1959; circa 1940-1959 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Club Officers and Financial, 1951 1961; 1951-1961 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Sunday School Records, 1960 1979; circa 1960-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Christian Education Committee, 1964 1965; 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Sunday School Financial Records, 1964 1966; 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sunday School Financial Records, 1975 1977; 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Missionary and Benevolence Committee, 1965 1985; 1965-1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Missions Correspondence, 1978 1990; 1978-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Inquirers' Class, 1980 1990; circa 1980-1990 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Christian Education Committee, 1987 1990; 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Missions Scholarship Applications, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Ministerial records, 1889 1990; 1889-1990; 1889 1928; 1889-1928
  This series contains records related to, and created by, the various ministers of the Pilgrim Congregational Church. The recordsconsists primarily of materials related to the installation and/or resignation of ministers from 1889-1928; not all ministers from this time period are represented. Records for Rev. Hubert Beckwith are more extensive and cover his entire tenure.
  - Rev. George Tewksbury resignation, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Rev. Charles Olmstead call and installation, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Pastoral search correspondence, 1900 1901; 1900-1901 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Rev. Richard Wright resignation, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Rev. Hubert Beckwith papers, 1922 1928; 1922-1928 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Rev. Stanley Addison installation, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Rev. Norman Bendroth pastoral evaluation, 1989 1990; 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Visual materials, 1898 1990; 1898-1990
  This series includes visual records, primarily photographs, and included are photographs of the church building and church members. The bulk of the photos are from the 1940s-1960s and from 1990. Some, but not all, of the photographs are labeled, identifying their subjects. There is also one folder containing two buttons from children's programs. The last box contains 75 lantern slides (housed in 6 smaller boxes), primarily of portraits of uniformed military members.
  - Intermediate Society photographs, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1940 1969; circa 1940-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Rev. Donald Wells ordination photographs, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Church committee photograph, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 125th anniversary newsletter photographs, 1898 1990; 1898-1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 125th anniversary celebration photographs, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Church building photographs, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Buttons, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lantern slides, undated (Box 10, Case 1-6)